Jon Hibbs

(270) 875-0545 (Home) 1610 March Lane Henderson, KY 42420 jon_hibbs@yahoo.com

Summary

I have 11 years of experience, including as a Warehouse Fork Lift Operator, as a Machine Operator and as a Carpet Cleaner Technician/Crew Chief in industries including Apparel and Accessory Stores, Wholesale Trade-Durable Goods and Personal Services.

Most recently, I have been working as a Warehouse Fork Lift Operator at Columbia Sportswear Distribution Center from April 2014 to June 2018.

My skills and experiences include: materials management.

I hold a High School Diploma degree in General from Madisonville North Hopkins High School.

Experience

Columbia Sportswear Distribution Center, Robards, KY

Apr. 2014 to Present

Warehouse Fork Lift Operator

Performed manual labor. Labeled containers. Read and interpreted work orders. Determined work assignments and equipment needs. Loaded and unloaded materials. Moved materials on worksites. Moved materials by hand, using heavy equipment. Packed containers. Inspected containers. Reported shortages and damaged materials. Ensured a clean and safe working environment. Followed all safety rules and regulations. Knowledge sets include: forklift operator, pallet jack, pallets, unloading, lift, load, general labor, packing. Moved freight, stock, and other materials to and from storage and production areas, loading docks, delivery vehicles, ships, and containers, by hand and using trucks, tractors, and other equipment. Read work orders and receive oral instructions to determine work assignments and material and equipment needs. Sorted cargo before loading and unloading. *Warehouse Fill-In Coordinator: instructed other employees to do different tasks, help others with questions about their job, and report safety and production issues to immediate Supervisors.

IAC, Madisonville, KY Oct. 2013 to Apr. 2014

Machine Operator

Adjusted machine feed and speed. Developed and verified Machine Control Data. Lifted workpieces to machines manually. Calculated position of cuts. Loaded and unloaded castings and raw materials in CNC machinery. Adjusted machine feed and speed, change cutting tools, and adjusted machine controls when automatic programming is faulty and if machines malfunction. Checked to ensure that workpieces are properly lubricated and cooled during machine operation. Conferred with supervisors and programmers to resolved machine malfunctions and production errors, and to obtain approval to continue production. Inserted controlled instructions into machine controlled units to start operation. Lifted workpieces to machines manually, and with hoists and cranes. Listened to machines during operation in order to detect sounds such as those made by dull cutting tools and excessive vibration and adjusted machines to compensate for problems. Set up and operated computer-controlled machines and robots to performed one and more machine functions on metal and plastic workpieces. Stacked and loaded finished items, and placed items on conveyor systems. Knowledge sets include: machine operator.

Stanley Steamer, Nebo, KY

Feb. 2007 to Oct. 2013

Carpet Cleaner Technician/Crew Chief

Performed heavy cleaning duties such as cleaning floors, shampooing rugs. Cleaned and operated company vehicles. Followed procedures for using chemical cleaners. Drove vehicles required to performed and travel to cleaning work, including vans, industrial trucks, and industrial vacuum cleaners. Followed procedures for the used of chemical cleaners and power equipment to prevent damage to floors and fixtures. Mixed water and detergents and acids in containers to prepared cleaning solutions, according to specifications. Moved heavy furniture, equipment, and supplies, either manually and by using hand trucks. Steamed cleaned and shampoo carpets. Stripped, sealed, finished, and polished floors.

Skills

Cnc, Communication Skills, Delivery, Forklift Operator, Machinery, Materials Management, Pallet Jack, Programming, Read, Safety

Education

2003 Madisonville North Hopkins High School, Madisonville, KY **High School Diploma**